
<Document>
    # Server Rules
    Welcome to Ronstation. This is a low-roleplay (LRP) server. Be sure to join our discord: https://discord.gg/q9vm8tfxc9.

    # Core rules:
    These rules apply at all times, including between rounds.

    ## C1: Enforcement of these rules is at the discretion of admins.
    Practice common sense while consulting these rules. The general idea counts, not the exact wording. The rules are guidelines for the server and should be interpreted to suit the situation at hand, not manipulated to suit your needs.

    Administrators can override rules or make interpretations if they deem it in the best interest of the current round, server, and/or community at large. However, administrators must answer for use of this privilege and be subject to accountability when doing so.

    ## C2: Don't be a jerk!
    Please be nice and respectful to each other and don't argue. Intentionally seeking to demean others due to their actual or perceived race, sex, gender, disability, orientation or the like is counterproductive and therefore prohibited. Do not try to ruin someone else’s good time. Being a jerk in-character is fine to a point, but being a jerk out of character is not welcome.

    Speciesism is prohibited, due to causing issues, especially if done to new players.

    ## C3: Please no erotic roleplay, shock content, or any other sexually suggestive content or themes.
    Generally, avoid anything that can come off as erotic. Don't say things like, “They're raping me!”. Lighter forms of affection like hugs and kisses are appropriate, as long as they are platonic.  Leeway is given to insults. Just don't push it too much.

    Things that appear to be intended to or are likely to disturb players out of character are considered shock content and are prohibited as a result.

    ## C4: Do not exploit the game, use cheats, or macros.
    The following are prohibited by this rule:
      - C4.1e: bugs and exploits which have effects that persist beyond the current round,
      - C4.2e: intentionally used bugs, exploits, and unintended behaviors which give the user an advantage over players who do not use them, even if their effects do not persist across rounds,
      - C4.3e: Creating and using multiple accounts in the same round (multi-keying),
      - C4.4e: evading or bypassing afk detection,
      - C4.5e: anything which results in gaining unauthorized elevated privileges, including admin permissions, whilst not an admin,
      - C4.6e: external tools and client modifications, including macros, and
      - C4.7e: anything which prevents another player who is not game banned from being able to play on the servers, not including in-character actions that do not persist across rounds.

    Both attempts and successful use are prohibited.

    ## C5: Please do not use LOOC chat, OOC chat, or other OOC means to share current round information (metacommunications).
    Do not utilize any external means of communication to talk to other players who were connected to the same server during the current round.

    Local Out of Character (LOOC) and Out of Character (OOC) channel are meant for things that don't relate to the current round. Using these channels to share round info is often referred to as "IC in OOC" or "ick ock".

    ## C6: Players must be at least 16 years of age.
    All players must be at least 16 years old. Additionally, all players must have a mental age of at least 16 years old. Administration may ban someone who they believe is acting less mature than a 16 year old, even if the player is known to be significantly older than 16 years old.

    # Roleplaying standards:
    These rules only apply during a round. A round ends only when the round summary has appeared. All of these rules apply fully until the moment that the round summary appears, even while the arrivals shuttle is in transit.
    Roleplay rules do not apply to ghosts/spectators/observers while they are ghosts/spectators/observers. Dead chat is considered to be an in-game out of character chat channel. Roleplay rules also do not apply during deathmatch and sandbox game modes.

    ## R1: Please roleplay as a coherent, believable character; this is a roleplaying game after all.
      - R1.1: Your words and actions ingame should be distinguishable as an in-universe character, and not as a person playing a game. Playstyles that disregard all opportunities for engagement and roleplay can be met with administrative action.
      - R1.2.1: Make a minimum effort to have your name fit in a setting involving a space station in the future. Honorifics and nicknames are allowed as long as only one additive is used at a time, i.e "James Williams Jr." or "James "One-Eye" Williams". Excessively OOC names are disallowed, and are defined as names which are intentionally hard to read/spell, references to in-game mechanics or OOC terminology, historical/famous/media, and any form of nonsensical or low-effort name. Clowns, mimes, silicons, wizards, and nuke ops have significantly more leeway in choosing their names, within reason.
      - R1.2.2: Species have naming conventions that are part of their in-universe culture. These may be subverted if they have a sufficient amount of in-character reasoning and effort explaining their non-standard name. Non-standard names are held to higher scrutiny and you may be questioned on why your name breaks these conventions.
      - R1.3: Character descriptions should only contain information that any other character couldn’t notice at a glance. The flavor text shouldn't contain any information about a feature (like personality, past, and so on) that isn't immediately apparent.
      - R1.4: You are, however, free to ask the administration questions about wether what you're about to do/were doing is acceptable under this ruleset.
      - R1.5: Usage of information you shouldn't have to gain advantage over others or otherwise break the round (metagaming) is prohibited, as it can not only result in a breach of immersion, but can ruin rounds for players.
      - R1.6: characters are allowed to have persistent knowledge/relationships/friendships with the caveat that knowledge of a character from previous rounds is not used maliciously. Likewise, Character friendships should not be exploitative in nature or be used to gain an unfair advantage.

    ## R2: Escalation must be reasonable.
    You may begin IC conflicts with another player if it does not excessively interfere with their ability to do their job. While you are allowed to escalate conflicts within reason, if it leads to violence and you have poor IC reasoning for inciting it, you may face administrative action.

    Killing a crewmate is a severe response, and requires severe justification to do so.

    Critically wounded or dead characters must be treated or taken to the medbay by the standing party where reasonable, and taking unnecessary action against a downed player opens you up to reprisal. If you are incapacitated in a fight and treated, or the conflict is otherwise meaningfully broken, you are expected to require an IC reason beyond 'bruised ego' to re-initiate it.

    ## R3: Don't act like an antagonist unless the game tells you that you are one (self-antag).
    You are not an antagonist unless the game tells you that you are an antagonist. Do not make yourself a major problem, annoyance, or disruption while not an antagonist. Do not willfully cooperate with known antagonists. Non-antagonists should typically either not have an overall effect on the round, or should have an overall positive effect on the round.

    ## R4: Do not powergame.
    Powergaming is using an in-game mechanic or game knowledge to give your own character an advantage at the expense of everyone else. Powergaming can take several forms, but it is generally rooted in playing-to-win or a focus on playing the game instead of roleplay. Examples are not limited to, but include:
      - R4.1e: Attempting to acquire weapons, explosives, poisons, or other dangerous items "just in case" you need them.
      - R4.2e: Hiding or otherwise make inaccessible antagonist objectives without sufficient IC reason.
      - R4.3e: As a non-antagonist, stealing departmental items at the expense of everyone else to amass mechanical advantages.
      - R4.4e: Going out of your way to hunt down antagonists without reasonable cause (valid hunting)(e.g. when there is no confirmed threat, or the alert level or the situation's danger levels are too low to warrant such a thing).
      - R4.5e: As an antagonist, going out of your way to cause mass-destruction or otherwise cause excessive damage beyond your objectives (may also fall under core rule C2).
      - R4.6e: Damaging, or otherwise making the starting terminal, arrivals shuttle, and the station's arrivals area uninhabitatable, even as an antagonist.

    ## R5: Stay in your lane.
    This means that you should do the job you signed up for and not try and do other people’s jobs for them or lay claim to their department. If you need something from another player you should attempt to ask them to get it for you instead of just taking it. Straying from your lane at the expense of another player should only be done where strictly necessary. Abandoning a role is prohibited, and includes not completing tasks that the role is expected to do, in addition to things like leaving the game.

    If you are a member of command, or any other important role (which is relayed to you in chat upon receiving your role) and you need to leave early, you should attempt to cryosleep if possible (and if you're a command member, you should notify command members that you're going to cryosleep).

    Furthermoe, some roles require additional rules to follow:
    - R5.1e: Antagonists should generally attempt to complete their objectives. Team antagonists should get along together and not fight each other while trying to complete their objectives.
    - R5.2e: Silicons (AI or borgs) must obey their laws, no matter the situation. They are, however, considered free-agents if they have no laws.
    - R5.3e: Familiars must always obey their master and follow every orders their master gives out.
    - R5.4e: Ghost roles sometimes have specific rulesets and instructions that you must follow.

    ## R6: Do not stall the round.
    Rounds are intended to end eventually. Don't hold a round hostage by preventing it from coming to a natural end. If a majority of players in a round want the round to end, don't prevent it from ending. Recalling the shuttle or preventing it from being called can contribute to round stalling, but is not always round stalling. Leaving the station with the nuclear authentication disk while nuclear operatives are trying to get it is almost always considered round stalling. Leaving the station on the evacuation shuttle is not round stalling.

    ## R7: Members of Command, Justice, and Security are held to a higher standard.
    All command, justice, and security roles are held to stricter interpretations of the rules.
      - R7.1. Command, Justice, and Security roles are not for inexperienced players. Members of command must know how to manage their team and be comptetent in their roles as commanding officers. Members of security are expected to know game basics and be more familiar with space law and server rules than a new player. Members of justice are expected to have sufficient knowledge of space law to execute their duties.
      - R7.2. Command, justice, and security should generally follow space law. Members of justice are required to have sufficient knowledge of space law.
      - R7.4. Do not hinder or cause overall negative effects to the station or crew as a member of command, justice, or security.
      - R7.5. Do not abuse your power as command, justice, or security.
</Document>
